Timble Michael

- +61 469 158 082
- ★ https://timblemichael.github.io/Resume/
- Sunshine Coast, Queensland, Australia

SUMMARY

An enthusiastic young professional with just over 2-years experience in the Engineering field. Currently, in the process of transforming my career into Data and Tech. Learning Python, Tableau, Front-end stack and back-end technology stack to push myself to be the best.

EXPERIENCE

Customer Service Agent

01/2022 - Present

Probe CX - Australian Taxation Office

- Exceeded 100% in average call handling time KPI indicator, indicating that I was able to handle more calls, in less time and achieve the desired results for the customer.
- Achieved 100% in adherence, conformance and attendance KPI indicators.
- Obtained a 'Understand and Applied' on all call quality reviews by the internal Quality team and external ATO team.

Graduate Mechanical Engineer (2nd Rotation)

07/2020 - 12/2021

Brisbane City Council - City Standards

- Led a team of 5 and successfully managed to conduct an audit of the aviation lights on the Eleanor Schonell Bridge. Collaborated with the communication team to notify the public and with Translink to attain permission to close the bridge for 1-night. Completed the project on time and on budget.
- Managed a team of 10 to perform asphalt repairs on the Walter Taylor Bridge. Collaborated with the communication team to notify the public and local police to attain permission to close the bridge for 4-nights and provide road safety. Completed ahead of time, and only slightly over budget.
- Led an internal team of 6 for removing crow's nest on the Brisbane Story Bridge. Collaborated with the communication team to make the public aware and local police to attain permission for closing the bridge and road safety. Completed on time and on budget.
- Managed an internal team of 5 for cleaning the underside on the northern section of the Brisbane Story Bridge.
 Collaborated with an external private contractor to install temporary scaffolding to ensure safety of the public. Completed on time and on budget.

Graduate Mechanical Engineer (1st Rotation)

01/2020 - 07/2020

Brisbane City Council - Fleet Management Services

- Collaborated with internal staff to plan, prepare, and execute testing of the modified air-conditioning system in Volvo B7
 Optimus and Volvo B7 Pre-Optimus buses to verify the expected functionality of the new system. An analysis report was submitted to the fleet engineer with the conclusions and approved the modifications to be added to the remaining fleet.
- · Assisted the quality coordinator in conducting audits for different bus depots.

EDUCATION

Academy Xi - Powered by Flatiron School (Online) - Software Engineering (Transform)

2022

Projects:

- Star Wars API Project. A project using the Star Wars API to display basic information about a character, planet, vehicle and show its image using a JSON server. Made with HTML/CSS/JavaScript.
- React Space API Project. A project using the NASA API and Planet API to create pages to show information about astronomy, Mars rover photos and planet. Made with React.
- React Weather API Project. A project using the weather API to show the weather in cities, and depending on the weather condition the background will change. Made with React

1/2

• Ruby Command Line Interface Application. A project that utilises the planet API and SQL database to provide information to the user depending on the user input.

University of Adelaide (Online) - Graduate Certificate in Data Science (Applied)

2022

Projects completed using Tableau and Jupyter notebook:

- COVID-19 Data Analysis using Python.
- Data Visualization using Tableau COVID-19 in the USA (link to Visualisation on LinkedIn)
- Data Visualization using Tableau AFL Data Analysis (link to Visualisation on LinkedIn)
- GPA 6.5/7.0

University of the Sunshine Coast - Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical) (Honours)

2019

- Honours Class I with a GPA of 6.5/7.0
- · Recipient of the L.E.W Mosel Prize in Engineering

SKILLS

Microsoft Excel Jupyter Notebook
Tableau Data Visualisation

HTML Power BI
CSS Teamwork
JavaScript Communication
React Quick Learner

Git Stakeholder Management

Ruby Critical Thinking
Python Presentation

Microsoft Project